Sharpen your senses.
≪感覚を研ぎ澄ませ≫
Be it the ball, the blockers,
≪ボルブロｯカスパイカ
or the spikers...
Don't overlook any movements on the court.
≪あらゆる動きを見逃すな≫
The perfect timing, and the perfect set for your spiker.
≪完璧なタイミングで
スパイカの最高打点を
捉える
Grasp it!
ピ
(菅原)また
Again...
It worked again!
(縁下)また決また
(木下)ひくり返したよ
They've turned it around!
Kageyama/Hinata    Tsukishima/Yamaguchi
They're one point away from winning the first set.
１セト先取まであと１点
(菅原)トスの精度が
すごい勢いで増していく
His sets are rapidly becoming more accurate!
Is this how good a setter Kageyama really is?
これがセタとして
本領を発揮した影山
(日向翔陽)やた
(田中)うしゃ
Dude, you're amazing!
But the one who drew all his abilities out...
≪でも
それを引張り出したのは
日向なんだよなぁ≫
was Hinata, wasn't it?
I scored again!
また決また
Episode Five:
A Wimp's Anxiety
≪よく我慢して待てたなぁ≫
Good job waiting for him. I'm proud of you!
((びゃ
I'd never even seen a guy take a set to his face before!
≪顔面にトス食らてるヤツなんて
初めて見たもんなぁ≫
(月島)そう何本も抜かせるか
I won't let you dominate!
Welcome!
(田中)いらしゃい
(縁下)うわ
フリで打たせたら触れねぇ
You won't even get near the ball if you leave him free!
ピピ
(月島)くそ
Dammit.
How'd you like that?
(田中)
どうだおら月島こら
Well, Tsukishima?
俺と日向潰すつたろうが
そうだそうだ
Didn't you say you'd target and crush Hinata and me?
Yeah!
Well, go ahead! If you can, that is!
やてみろやおら
みろやおら
If you can, that is!
(菅原)なんでお前が
いちばん威張てんの田中
Why are you running your mouth, Tanaka?
え
(縁下)そうだ
Kageyama/Hinata    Tsukishima/Yamaguchi
Yeah, why?
You can only spike because of those first-years!
１年のおかげで打ててるくせに
Quit acting like a hotshot!
(菅原)態度でかいぞ
(木下)脱ぐなハゲ
Keep your shirt on, cueball!
Kageyama/Hinata    Tsukishima/Yamaguchi
All right, which one of you just casually insulted me?!
(田中)今
普通に悪口混ぜたの誰だこら
Frankly,
(木下)正直影山と日向の
あの攻撃を止めらんなきゃ
Tsukishima's team had better figure out a way to stop Kageyama and Hinata
決定力に欠ける月島チムは
きついよなぁ
or else they're gonna have a hard time,
considering they lack attacking firepower.
(成田)第２セト始めます
It's time to begin the second set.
行くぞ
(２人)おす
Let's go!
Yeah!
All right!
ピ
おしゃ
Tsukishima/Yamaguchi    Kageyama/Hinata
All right!
ぶぐわ
Tsukishima/Yamaguchi    Kageyama/Hinata
(月島)あ
ピ
Tsukishima/Yamaguchi    Kageyama/Hinata
(田中)シャラァ
ピ
Take this!
Tsukishima/Yamaguchi    Kageyama/Hinata
(木下)影山確かにすげぇけど
Kageyama may be awesome,
but making those precise sets
looks like it's taking its toll on him.
すんごい神経すり減らしそうだな
あの精密なトス
(縁下)日向も普通の何倍も
動き回てしんどそうだ
Hinata seems worn out due to running around way more than typical.
うんでも
Yeah, but still...
(２人)うおし
Yes!
楽しそうだ
ピピ
They look like they're having fun!
Tsukishima/Yamaguchi    Kageyama/Hinata
(菅原)お疲れさん
Good game.
(田中)
だ大地さんもスガさんも
D-Daichi, Suga...
あいつらに
あんな攻撃使えるて見抜いて
Did you say all that because you knew they could run plays like that?
あんなこと言たんすか
マジパねぇす
You're incredible!
(２人)え
(澤村)
((コンビネションが使えたら
Get them to work in combination and
Karasuno will evolve by leaps and bounds!
烏野は爆発的に進化する
((なんかうまいこと
使てやれんじゃないの
Can't you put them to good use?
そんなわけあるか
As if, dumbass!
俺はもと日向が打ちやすいトス
上げたれよて意味で言たんだよ
I meant he should make sets that Hinata would find easy to hit.
(澤村)俺は影山の
多少ムチャなトスにも
As for me,
I thought Hinata could learn to keep up with Kageyama's somewhat unreasonable sets.
日向なら合わせられるように
なるかなて思てた
でもいい意味で裏切られたなぁ
(田中)ん
But they betrayed my expectations in a good way.
(日向･影山)はぁはぁ
(澤村)なんていうか
How should I put this?
こうなればいいなと
思てたのが
I was hoping for this to happen, but instead,
こうなちゃたみたいな
this is what we ended up with.
未熟でも天性のスピドやバネを
持ている日向
Hinata's inexperienced, but he's got natural speed and jumping ability.
And Kageyama's skills allow him to put them to great use.
その能力を
高い技術で完璧に生かす影山
互いが互いの能力を
最大限に引き出す
The two of them bring out the best in each other.
What? Do you have a problem?
(澤村)これは予想以上に
すごいコンビができちゃたかもな
They might be a better duo than we ever imagined.
Of course I do!
ほら行くぞ月島
Come on, let's go.
Tsukishima!
(月島)え何
What?
試合の最初と最後に
握手すんじゃん
We're supposed to shake hands before and after every match.
今日の最初はしてないけど
Though we did forgot about it earlier.
Besides, we're gonna be teammates from now on.
それに
これからチムメイトだし
Not that I'm happy about it.
うれしくねぇけど
Hurry up, man!
早くしろよ
お前知らねぇのちゃんと
チｰムメイトの自覚を持たないと
Don't you know?
If you don't treat your teammates with respect, you'll get thrown out of the gym!
体育館から放り出されるんだぞ
But you guys got banned from the gym
(月島)君らが
体育館出禁になたのは
because you ignored the captain's
orders and began some farcical contest
キャプテンの注意をシカトして
勝手に勝負始めた挙句
which led to you sending the Vice Principal's wig flying.
教頭のヅラを
吹飛ばしたからでしょ
いいいじゃねぇか
細かいことは
Don't be so nitpicky.
はい握手
(月島)何すんだこの来るな
Come on, shake hands!
What are you doing?
Stay away!
Stop it!
やめろ
(田中)何やてんだ１年ども
What the hell are they doing?
大丈夫かツキ
(澤村)月島
Are you okay, Tsukki?
Tsukishima.
どうだた３対３は
How'd you like the three-on-three?
(月島)別にどうでも
エリト校の王様相手だし
I didn't really care for it.
We were up against a king from an elite school.
It's no surprise that we plebeians couldn't beat him.
僕ら庶民が勝てなくても
何も不思議じゃないです
(澤村)ふんその割にはさ
You say that,
ちゃんと本気だたじゃんほい
but you did get serious back there.
Here.
キャプテン
(澤村)何
Captain!
What?
Club Application
Volleyball
Class 1-3 Kageyama Tobio
Club Application
Volleyball
Class 1-1 Hinata Shouyou
Club Application
Volleyball
Class 1-3 Kageyama Tobio
Club Application
Volleyball
Class 1-1 Hinata Shouyou
Club Application
Volleyball
Class 1-3 Kageyama Tobio
Club Application
Volleyball
Class 1-1 Hinata Shouyou
Club Application
Volleyball
Class 1-3 Kageyama Tobio
Club Application
Volleyball
Class 1-1 Hinata Shouyou
Club Application
Volleyball
Class 1-3 Kageyama Tobio
Club Application
Volleyball
Class 1-1 Hinata Shouyou
Club Application
Volleyball
Class 1-3 Kageyama Tobio
Club Application
Volleyball
Class 1-1 Hinata Shouyou
Club Application
Volleyball
Class 1-3 Kageyama Tobio
Club Application
Volleyball
Class 1-1 Hinata Shouyou
Club Application
Volleyball
Class 1-3 Kageyama Tobio
Club Application
Volleyball
Class 1-1 Hinata Shouyou
Club Application
Volleyball
Class 1-3 Kageyama Tobio
Club Application
Volleyball
Class 1-1 Hinata Shouyou
Club Application
Volleyball
Class 1-3 Kageyama Tobio
Club Application
Volleyball
Class 1-1 Hinata Shouyou
Club Application
Volleyball
Class 1-3 Kageyama Tobio
Club Application
Volleyball
Class 1-1 Hinata Shouyou
Club Application
Volleyball
Class 1-3 Kageyama Tobio
Club Application
Volleyball
Class 1-1 Hinata Shouyou
Club Application
Volleyball
Class 1-3 Kageyama Tobio
Club Application
Volleyball
Class 1-1 Hinata Shouyou
Club Application
Volleyball
Class 1-3 Kageyama Tobio
Club Application
Volleyball
Class 1-1 Hinata Shouyou
Club Application
Volleyball
Class 1-3 Kageyama Tobio
Club Application
Volleyball
Class 1-1 Hinata Shouyou
Club Application
Volleyball
Class 1-3 Kageyama Tobio
Club Application
Volleyball
Class 1-1 Hinata Shouyou
Club Application
Volleyball
Class 1-3 Kageyama Tobio
Club Application
Volleyball
Class 1-1 Hinata Shouyou
Club Application
Volleyball
Class 1-3 Kageyama Tobio
Club Application
Volleyball
Class 1-1 Hinata Shouyou
Club Application
Volleyball
Class 1-3 Kageyama Tobio
Club Application
Volleyball
Class 1-1 Hinata Shouyou
Club Application
Volleyball
Class 1-3 Kageyama Tobio
Club Application
Volleyball
Class 1-1 Hinata Shouyou
Club Application
Volleyball
Class 1-3 Kageyama Tobio
Club Application
Volleyball
Class 1-1 Hinata Shouyou
Club Application
Volleyball
Class 1-3 Kageyama Tobio
Club Application
Volleyball
Class 1-1 Hinata Shouyou
Club Application
Volleyball
Class 1-3 Kageyama Tobio
Club Application
Volleyball
Class 1-1 Hinata Shouyou
Club Application
Volleyball
Class 1-3 Kageyama Tobio
Club Application
Volleyball
Class 1-1 Hinata Shouyou
Club Application
Volleyball
Class 1-3 Kageyama Tobio
Club Application
Volleyball
Class 1-1 Hinata Shouyou
Club Application
Volleyball
Class 1-3 Kageyama Tobio
Class 1-1 Hinata Shouyou
Club Application
Volleyball
Class 1-3 Kageyama Tobio
Class 1-1 Hinata Shouyou
Volleyball
Class 1-3 Kageyama Tobio
Class 1-1 Hinata Shouyou
Volleyball
Class 1-3 Kageyama Tobio
Class 1-1 Hinata Shouyou
Volleyball
Class 1-3 Kageyama Tobio
Class 1-1 Hinata Shouyou
Volleyball
Class 1-3 Kageyama Tobio
Class 1-1 Hinata Shouyou
Volleyball
Class 1-3 Kageyama Tobio
Class 1-1 Hinata Shouyou
Volleyball
Class 1-3 Kageyama Tobio
Class 1-1 Hinata Shouyou
Volleyball
Class 1-3 Kageyama Tobio
Class 1-1 Hinata Shouyou
Volleyball
Class 1-3 Kageyama Tobio
Class 1-1 Hinata Shouyou
(澤村)
清水あれもう届いてたよな
Shimizu!
They arrived, right?
Yes.
｢あれ｣
"They"?
ああうほぉ
(清水)たぶん
サイズ大丈夫だと思うけど
Those sizes should fit you,
but let me know if you have a problem.
何かあたら言て
(２人)あざす
Thank you!
お前も着てみろよ
いや僕はあとで
Try it on!
Nah, I'll do it later.
What, are you shy?
恥ずかしがり屋か
いいじゃねぇか着てみろ
Come on, just try it on.
(一同)
着ろ着ろ着ろ着ろ
Try it on! Try it on! Try it on! Try it on!
(２人)おお
ほはは
(田中)おう似合てるぞ
Yeah, lookin' good.
(菅原)
うん似合てる似合てるぞ
I agree. It looks good on you.
Lookin' good!
From now on, you're members of Karasuno's volleyball team.
(澤村)
これから烏野バレ部として
One, two, go!
せの
(一同)よろしく
Welcome to the team!
Thanks!
And then, you do this!
一応ひと段落ついたな
(２人)ん
Well, I guess things got sorted out.
Like this?
You and Tanaka did your best to make sure that happened, right?
(澤村)スガも田中もなんか
いろいろやてくれたんだろ
Huh? We didn't really do anything.
(菅原)えいや別に何も
とりあえず
丸く収まてよかた
Anyway, I'm glad things worked out for the best.
ありがとな
Thanks a bunch.
(清水･菅原)お疲れ
(澤村)なんだおい
Good work, Cap'n.
What's gotten into you two?
おい日向休んだか休んだな
Hey, Hinata!
You've had enough of a break, I take it.
もかいクイクの練習すんぞ
Let's get back to practicing quick attacks while it's still fresh in our minds.
感覚残てるうちに
おお
Sure!
田中さん
ボル出しお願いします
Tanaka, please pass for us.
What? Already?
(田中)げもう動くのかよ
≫(武田)組めた組めたよ
I did it!
I arranged one!
練習試合相手は県のベスト４
A practice match!
Our opponents are one of the top four teams in the prefecture: Aoba Jousai High!
青葉城西高校
(菅原)青城
Seijou?
げ
うそ
Ack.
No way.
A practice match against one of the prefecture's top four?!
県ベスト４と練習試合
青葉城西
Aoba Jousai...
(武田)お
君らが問題の日向君と影山君か
Oh, you two must be the Hinata and Kageyama I've heard so much about.
誰先生
知らねぇ
Who's he? A teacher?
Beats me.
(武田)今年からバレ部顧問の
I'm Takeda Ittetsu, the volleyball team's advisor starting this year.
武田一鉄です
(２人)おす
Hello.
バレの経験はないから
技術的な指導はできないけど
I don't have any experience with volleyball, so I can't really coach you guys,
それ以外のところは
全力で頑張るからよろしく
but I'll do my best to take care of everything else.
Nice to meet you.
(２人)おす
(澤村)先生
Likewise, sir!
Sir...
(武田)いやあちこち
練習試合のお願いに行てたから
Oh, I've been running all over the place trying to find us an opponent, so I haven't had any time to show up here.
全然こちに顔出せなくて
How'd you get such a strong team to agree?
(菅原)先生青城なんて強いとこと
どうやて
Don't tell me you kowtowed again...
(澤村)まさかまた土下座を
(武田)してないしてない
I didn't!
I'm great at kowtowing, but I didn't do it this time.
土下座得意だけど
してないよ今回は
ただ条件があてね
(澤村)条件
Just... they only agreed under one condition.
A condition?
(武田)影山君を
セタとしてフルで出すこと
Kageyama must play as setter for the entire match.
あ
え
なんすかそれ
烏野自体は興味はないけど
What's that supposed to mean?
They have no interest in Karasuno, but they wanna take precautions against Kageyama?
影山だけはとりあえず
警戒しときたいてことすか
They lookin' down on us? Turnin' their noses up?
なんすかなめてんすか
ペロペロすか
いいや
そういうわけじゃなくて
I-It's not like that...
(菅原)いいじゃないか
こんなチャンスそうないだろ
I don't see a problem. An opportunity like this doesn't come along too often.
(田中)いいんすかスガさん
烏野の正セタ
Seriously?
You're our starting setter, you know!
スガさんじゃないすか
(菅原)俺は
I...
俺は日向と影山のあの攻撃が
I wanna see how effective Hinata and Kageyama's plays will be against one of the big four.
４強相手にどのくらい
通用するのか見てみたい
先生詳細お願いします
うんえと
Please give us the details, sir.
Okay.
Well, this might be a bit sudden, but the match's next Tuesday.
日程は急なんだけど来週の火曜
放課後の短い時間だから
１ゲムだけ
There's not much time after school,
so you'll only be playing one best-of-three.
We'll be using a school bus to travel there.
≪試合試合
A match!
As soon as homeroom ends...
This will be my first match at Karasuno with a full lineup!
≪烏野に来て最初の
正式な人数でやる試合だ≫
(武田)遅れないようにね
(一同)はい
Don't be late.
Yes, sir!
Dismissed!
(成田)お疲れした
(縁下･木下)した
Thank you, sir!
≪菅原さん
Sugawara!
今回は俺
自動的にスタメンですけど
I got into the starting lineup by default this time,
次はちゃんと
実力でレギュラ取ります
but I'll earn my spot next time!
え
あいや影山は俺なんか
眼中にないと思てたから意外で
I didn't expect you to take notice of me, so I'm a little surprised.
Why wouldn't I?
(菅原)体力も実力も
断然お前の方が上だろ
Well, you're physically and technically far better than me.
But you have way more experience.
It won't be easy to make up for that.
経験の差はそう簡単に
埋まるもんじゃないです
それと
≪(田中)スガさん
Also...
Suga!
Sugawara!
(澤村)スガ
菅原さん
ほほかのメンバからの
Y-You also have the t-t-trust of the other members.
しし信頼とか
≪おお中学のあの試合
本人的に相当こたえてんだな≫
He must still be hurting from
that match back in junior high.
なので俺負けません
There you have it.
I'm coming for you!
うん俺も負けない
And I won't go down without a fight.
スガさん大地さんが
肉まんおごてくれるて
Suga!
Daichi said he'll treat us to some meat buns!
(菅原)
でもさ影山青葉城西て
But hey, Kageyama,
Foot of the Slope
don't a lot of players from Kitagawa First
eventually go to high school at Aoba Jousai?
北川第一の選手の
大部分が進む高校だよな
Oh, yeah.
ああまあそうすね
≪影山の
元チムメイトがいる高校
Kageyama's former teammates must go there...
いやその
やりづらくないかと思てさ
Well, you know, I was wondering if that'd make things harder for you.
ん同じチムだたら
考えるかもしれないけど
Maybe if we'd ended up on the same team, sure,
戦うなら
ただ全力でやるだけです
but if I'm taking them on, I'll just give it my all.
そうかそうだな
おす
That so? I guess that makes sense.
Yeah.
(田中)でもいいんすかスガさん
俺は
Are you really okay with this, Suga?
I...
I can't accept it!
俺は納得いかないつうか
そりゃ悔しいけどでも
It does hurt, of course, but even so,
影山が中学んときと
同じだと思たら大間違いだて
I want them to see just how mistaken they are if they think Kageyama hasn't changed since junior high.
見せてやりたいじゃん
≫ガラガラガラ
Agreed.
(澤村)そうだな
おおお
And let's show them that Kageyama's not the
only reason they should be scared of our team.
怖いのは影山単品じゃない
てとこ見せてやろう
なあ日向
Right, Hinata?
あおふ
Wighd, Gabden!
Who gave you permission to start stuffing your face?!
(田中)お前何先に食てんだよ
ふざけんな
Screw you!
(繋心)おいバレ部ども
店の前で騒ぐな
Hey, volleyball team!
Quit making a scene in front of the store!
(２人)サセン
うが
We're sorry.
≪そうかバレ部か
Oh...
Volleyball team, huh?
≪ここにいるみんな
バレ部なんだ
Everyone here is part of the team.
同じ≫
We're on...
あざす
カレまんないすか
Thank you.
Are there any curry buns?
You'd better not skip dinner after this.
(繋心)晩飯ちゃんと食えよ
Hey! Come and get some too!
おいお前らも食えよ
(山口)あざす
Thank you!
≪同じチムなんだ≫
We're on the same team!
(澤村)影山
それ食たらちょといい
Kageyama, let me have a moment once you're done eating.
Sure.
(繋心)騒ぐなよ
(菅原)うす
Keep it down, you hear me?
Okay.
I was wondering which position to use Hinata in for the practice match.
(澤村)今度の練習試合の
日向のポジションを
どうしようかと思てさ
お前どう思う
What do you think?
Haikyuu !!
(澤村)
で練習試合のポジションだけど
So, about the lineup for the practice match...
これでいこうと思う
I think we should go with this.
Tanaka
Hinata
Sawamura
Kageyama
Tsukishima
Ennoshita
Sugawara
Yamaguchi
Kinoshita
Narita
(澤村)影山と日向は
セトで使いたいし
We want to use Kageyama and Hinata as a set.
(２人)≪セト
A set...
And Tsukishima is one of the very few tall players we have.
(澤村)月島は
うちでは数少ない長身選手だ
青城相手に
どれくらい戦えるか見たい
I wanna see how they fare against Seijou.
Okaaay.
≪１年俺だけ外れた
I'm the only first-year who missed out.
(田中)ていうか
でかさが重要なポジションに
Why's Hinata in a position which places importance on height?
日向すか
え
Middle blocker?
ミドルブロカて
ノｯポ野郎月島と同じポジシｮン
Am I playing the same position as Tsukishima the beanpole?
Volleyball
あちょちょと
ポジションおさらいしていい
Volleyball
H-Hang on. Mind if I review the positions?
Setters
Setters:
(武田)
スパイクのためのトスを上げ
their primary task being setting for spikes,
they're playmakers who orchestrate a team's offense.
攻撃を組み立てる司令塔
Wing spikers
Wing spikers:
(武田)攻撃の中核を担う
攻守のバランスが取れた
the nucleus of a team's offense, they're also
all-rounders who can handle both attack and defense.
オルラウンダ
Middle blockers
Middle blockers:
(武田)
ブロクで相手の攻撃を阻み
they block opposition attacks and
also score points via quick attacks.
主にクイクで得点更に
Also, they act as decoys to lure in opposition blocks.
囮として
敵のブロクを引き付ける
こんな感じでオケ
Is that okay?
There are other positions,
like ones that specialize in defense,
ほかにも
守備専門とかあるんですが
but that'll do for now.
今回はそれでオケです
いいか日向
Listen up, Hinata.
お前は最強の囮だ
You are the greatest decoy!
The greatest...
最強の囮
de... coy?
なんかパとしねぇ
クイクでガンガン点を稼いで
I'm not too happy about this.
We'll rack up a bunch of points using quick attacks and make the opposition's defense focus on you.
敵ブロクの注意を
お前に向けさせる
そうすれば
ほかのスパイカが生きてくる
That'll make things easier for the other spikers.
あ
月島みたいなでかいヤツが
Oh!
If a bunch of tall guys like Tsukishima were to stupidly fall for your tricks,
何人もお前の動きに
アホみたいに引掛かたら
気持ちいいだろ
うおいいそれいい
wouldn't it feel great?
That sounds really good!
おいアホて
ツキのことじゃないだろうな
Hey! You'd better not be calling Tsukki stupid!
黙れよ山口
ごめんツキ
Shut up, Yamaguchi.
Sorry, Tsukki.
逆にお前が機能しなきゃ
On the other hand,
assume that our entire offense will
collapse if you don't prove effective.
ほかの攻撃も総崩れになると思え
う
ちょとあんま
プレシャかけんなよ
Hey!
Don't put too much pressure on the guy!
Collapse...
(澤村)ほら見なさい
Look what you've done!
But what about blocking? That's just as important.
(田中)でも肝心のブロクは
どうすんだよ
No matter how high his vertical,
いくら高く跳べても
もともとでかいヤツと比べたら
it's gonna take him more time to reach the
peak of his jump in comparison to taller guys.
ジャンプのてぺんに
到達するまでの時間がかかるだろ
はいだから日向が
ブロクで重点を置くのは
Yeah.
So Hinata's gonna have to focus less on knocking down opposition spikes
相手のスパイクを
たたき落とすよりも
触ること
and more on touching them.
日向のバカみたいな
反射速度を生かして
We're gonna use his ridiculously high reaction speed
敵のスパイクに
とにかく触て勢いを弱め
and have him slow down opposition spikes by touching them somehow,
I got it!
確実に拾て
カウンタを仕掛ける
which will give us a better chance
to dig them out and counterattack.
そんないきなり
うまいこといくか
Will that really work?
It probably won't.
(澤村)いかないだろうな
え
少なくとも最初は
Not immediately, at least.
でもやてみれば
何かしら分かることがあるよ
But I'm sure we'll learn something by trying it out.
練習試合なんだしさ
(田中)おす
It is a practice match, after all.
Right.
(澤村)何より空中戦で
日向の高さにかなうヤツ
More than anything,
Tsukishima and Kageyama are the only people on our
team who can match Hinata's vertical in an aerial battle.
うちのチムじゃ
月島と影山くらいだ
だから日向自信持て
はい俺頑張ります
So believe in yourself, Hinata...
Yes, sir! I'll do my best!
いぱい点取て囮もやて
サブもブロｯクもクイｯクも
I'll score a lot of points, act as a decoy,
serve, block, and run quick attacks!
ちょちょちょちょ落ち着け
うわ
Whoa, whoa! Calm down!
ショトした
日向がショトした
He short-circuited!
Hinata short-circuited!
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]ｷｰﾝｺｰﾝｶｰﾝｺｰﾝ(ﾁｬｲﾑ)
(道宮)あ澤村
Sawamura!
(澤村)おう道宮何
Hey, Michimiya.
What's up?
(道宮)明日青城と
試合するんだてよく組めたね
I heard you're playing Seijou tomorrow.
I'm surprised you managed to arrange that.
(澤村)ああうん
武田先生が頑張てくれてさ
Oh, yeah.
Mr. Takeda did his best.
Aren't you scared, though?
(道宮)でも怖くない
青城て確か
去年も県でベスト４だたよね
Didn't Seijou reach the prefectural semifinals last year?
コテンパンにされちゃうかもてさ
(澤村)ふふふ
Aren't you scared they'll destroy you?
実は結構
面白い１年が入てきてさぁ
The thing is, some pretty interesting first-years joined us recently.
(道宮)あ知てる入部早々
教頭のカツラ飛ばしたていう
Oh, I've heard about them.
You mean the ones who sent the Vice Principal's wig flying right after they joined—
(澤村)
ああちょちょちょちょ
Whoa there!
しぃ
うんうん
They're still a work in progress,
まだまだ未完成なんだけどさ
あいつらが機能すれば
but if they prove effective,
烏野は爆発的に
進化するんじゃないかて
I think Karasuno can improve by leaps and bounds.
思うんだよね
へえ
１年も部室使ていいんすか
(菅原)うんかまわないよ
Can first-years really use the clubroom too?
Yeah. No problem.
(菅原)おす
(一同)ちす
Hey!
Hello!
Excuse us!
(影山･日向)失礼します
おお
ふふ
そんなに驚くようなもんか
Did this really make your jaw drop?
It's just a normal clubroom, isn't it?
普通の部室だろ
俺部室とか初めてなんです
I've never actually been in a clubroom before.
あ小さな巨人も
ここ使てたんですよね
The Little Giant once used this place too, right?
(田中)いよいよ明日
デビュ戦じゃねぇか日向
You finally make your debut tomorrow, Hinata.
う
ま練習試合だけどよ
Though it's just a practice match.
青城の体育館はでかいぞ
選手もみんなでかいから
Seijou's gym is huge, y'know.
All of their players are too,
so be careful you don't get intimidated.
ビビんなよ
ちす
Hey.
Hey!
おす
ちわす
Hello there!
ビ
As...
As?
ビビるわけないじゃないですか
As if I'd ever get intimidated.
I'll steal the spotlight, and...
絶対すんげぇ大活躍して
(田中)日向よ
Hinata, my boy.
お前がはこうとしてる
それ上着だけど
You know that thing you're trying to wear?
It's a jacket.
なははははどうした
What's the matter? Is that supposed to be fashionable?
Kageyama...
影山明日日向大丈夫か
Is Hinata gonna be all right tomorrow?
You look ridiculous!
ん大丈夫て
What do you mean?
(澤村)
日向これまでの試合経験て
I mean, the only match experience he's had is that match back in junior high.
Dude, just how panicked are you?
中学のあの試合だけて言うし
N-N-Not at all!
So a match must mean the world to him. And that'd only make him more anxious.
その分思い入れも不安も
すんげぇ強いと思うんだよね
I-I-I was just trying to play the fool! It was on purpose!
You're stuttering way too much, man!
だから相当
緊張してんじゃないかて
I bet he's a nervous wreck right now.
ん緊張くらい
誰だてするんじゃ
But doesn't everyone get nervous bef—
Oh, come on!
(菅原)ああほらもう
お前のその感じ
I can't believe you!
小心者の緊張なめてる
はあ
You're totally underestimating a wimp's anxiety!
俺が何言ても
プレシャになるみたいでさ
No matter what I say to him, it only seems to put him under even more pressure.
(澤村)((日向部室の鍵だけどさ
Hinata.
About the key to the clubroom...
((大丈夫です持ていきます
(澤村)((あいや
It's all right! I'll keep it with me!
That's not it. I brought it because I hadn't told you where we usually keep it.
置き場所教えてなかたから
持てきたんだけど
((すみませんすみません
すみませんすみません
I'm sorry!
最初のうちは
しかたないんじゃないすか
That's just how it goes at the beginning.
下手にいじんない方が
It'd probably be better to just leave him alone.
そうか
You think?
≪明日はちゃんとやんないと
I have to play well tomorrow.
≪中学とか
この前の３対３と違て
Unlike junior high or the three-on-three the other day, from now on...
これからは
俺の代わりがいる
I can be replaced!
≪うぅ嫌だ交代嫌だ
No!
I don't wanna be subbed out!
I'm finally getting the chance to stand on the court with actual teammates.
≪せかくチムメイトが
そろてるコトに立てるんだ≫
≪ちゃんと最後まで出たい
I wanna play the entire match!
う
ヘマしちゃダメだ
I can't screw up.
あららごめん
小さくて見えなかた
Oh, sorry about that.
You're so tiny that I couldn't see you.
いひひひ
あうん
O-Okay.
ヘマしちゃダメだ
I can't screw up.
(月島)なんだあれ
(山口)さあ
The hell's up with him?
Who knows?
おい影山お前日向に
いつもの余計なひと言で
Hey, Kageyama.
Huh? Where'd my pants go?
Don't put Hinata under any more pressure by
saying something unnecessary like you always do.
ムダにプレシｬかけんなよ
え余計なひと言
Unnecessary?
≪そんなこと
俺言たことあるか
Have I ever done that?
≪全然心当たりがない≫
It's not ringing any bells.
ん
(一同)≪自覚なしかよ
He's not aware of it?
(田中)はぁはぁはぁ日向
え
Hinata!
(田中)下それ俺のジｬジだよ
えあ
Those are my pants, dude!
≫何やてんのよ田中変態
What's wrong with you, Tanaka? You pervert!
え
≫バカじゃないの最低
Are you retarded? Disgusting!
寝れねぇ
I can't sleep!
≫寝れねぇ寝れねぇ寝れねぇ
寝れねぇ寝れねぇ寝れねぇ
(夏)兄ちゃんうるさい
Keep it down, Bro!
ごごめん
(夏)んん
S-Sorry.
Kitagawa First
Volleyball Team
(澤村)整列
Line up!
(一同)お願いします
(武田)あい
If you could, please!
Sure.
うははははおい日向
食い物やるぞ食い
Here, Hinata. Have a snack.
えお前何その顔
え
What's with that face, man?
あちょと
昨日眠れなくてう
Oh, I kinda couldn't sleep last night...
ま窓窓開けてもいい
(田中)ええ
W-Window...
Mind if I open the window?
う
(田中)うわ
うお止めて
Stop!
≪あれ
≪なんか
Huh?
This kinda looks...
≪予想以上に
...worse than we thought.
(３人)≪ヤバい
Are we in big trouble?!
(菅原)大地日向大丈夫かな
(澤村)ううん
Next Episode Preview
(菅原)
大地なんか顔色悪いけど
Daichi, will Hinata be all right?
(澤村)
なんか臭いで俺も酔てきた
Daichi? You look kinda pale.
(菅原)
窓みんな窓全開にして
The stench made me nauseous too...
The windows! Guys, open all the windows!
Episode Six:
An Amusing Team
Next time on Haikyuu!!:
"An Amusing Team."
今日午後､新潟県上越市の海岸で
子ども３人がおぼれ､
助けようとした大人２人も海に流
された